<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Agrielio De Lazo II</title>
    <link>https://avdlii.xyz/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Agrielio De Lazo II</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://avdlii.xyz/img/terminal.png</url>
      <link>https://avdlii.xyz/img/terminal.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 19:48:06 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://avdlii.xyz/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Troubeshooting Homelab Issue: Media Server</title>
      <link>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/troubeshooting-jellyfin-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 19:48:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/troubeshooting-jellyfin-server/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting my media server issues</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you ever experience this kind of scenario?</p>
<p>You wake up, do your usual morning routine. Wake your machine up, glance at the server dashboard where everything seems fine. Why wouldn&rsquo;t it be when you just used it last night before sleep? But its not. Everything is not working.</p>
<p>This is what happened to me today. I was having my usual morning routine, and upon opening my media server I got an error message <code>Playback error</code> which is weird because I played this same media file last night</p>
<p>How? Why?</p>
<p>I use this server everyday. I used it last night. And when I woke up it doesn&rsquo;t work anymore.</p>
<p>So then, time to spend my weekend putting on my imaginary &lsquo;deer stalker&rsquo; hat and Sherlock the crap out of this.</p>
<h2 id="docker">Docker</h2>
<p>First suspect is of course, the one who should be running things: Docker.</p>
<p>I spent a good amount of time analyzing my <code>docker-compose</code> file. Everything seems in order. I changed the volume mounts of the media files for my jellyfin server in case this is a permission issue.
<br>
No change.
<br>
I changed the ports because maybe something is interfering with the port number of jellyfin.
<br>
Problem persists.
<br>
I then tried to upgrade the docker and docker-compose version.
<br>
No dice.
<br>
So okay.. maybe docker is innocent, but I&rsquo;m keeping a close eye..</p>
<h2 id="jellyfin">Jellyfin</h2>
<p>Next suspect: Jellyfin</p>
<p>Maybe the application had an update? Maybe some configuration changed along with the update? I scoured their official github page and their official website for references but there&rsquo;s no such update. If anything, Jellyfin is quite stable.
<br>
I then checked the page if there are misconfigurations that I somehow did. But, the server is working for almost a month now. Why now? Why today?
<br>
Jellyfin seems good.. moving on.</p>
<h2 id="linux-ownerships-and-permissions">Linux (Ownerships and Permissions)</h2>
<p>After checking Jellyfin and coming up empty, I decided to focus my attention to the OS. I checked some files in my media directory. Yeah, some files still have <code>root:root</code> ownerships with <code>700</code> permissions. Maybe if I change that, the error will be fixed.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#ebdbb2;background-color:#282828;-moz-tab-size:2;-o-tab-size:2;tab-size:2;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sudo chown -R dufresne:dufresne /opt/jellyfin_media
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>sudo chmod -R <span style="color:#d3869b">755</span> /opt/jellyfin_media
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Still nothing! Same error.</p>
<h2 id="browser-compatibility">Browser compatibility</h2>
<p>I maybe grasping at straws with this one but better to leave no stones unturned.
<br>
I used every browser I know of: Google Chrome, Safari, Firefox, Arc, Opera</p>
<p>Yup, same issue. At this point, I am close to making a new virtual machine and delete the old one, but should the issue come up again, would I remake another VM in order to fix things? No. I don&rsquo;t need a band-aid. I need a fix..</p>
<h2 id="linux-disks">Linux (Disks)</h2>
<p>My homelab has a passthrough to my old external hard drive. The hard drive itself is quite old. So maybe this is a hardware issue? To test this, I plugged my external hard drive in my other machine and spin up a jellyfin container just to test if the media is playable.
<br>
And what do you know? It played.
<br>
<br>
I learned two things from this:</p>
<ol>
<li>The disk is okay. (Kudos to Western Digital, this has been my external hard drive since 2013)</li>
<li>The issue is isolated within my homelab. Since the media played in my other machine.
<br>
<br>
There&rsquo;s hope after all..</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="proxmox">Proxmox</h2>
<p>Since this maybe a homelab issue, I dove into my homelab OS: Proxmox.</p>
<p>I checked if I am running out of storage. Thankfully I am not. I checked for VM settings, I&rsquo;ve read somewhere that sometimes disks re-mount themselves, coming up with different UUIDs. Different UUIDs are problematic in a media server since the metadata is referencing the disk mounts.
<br>
I cannot find evidence that the disks re-mounted so what I did was delete all the metadata in the jellyfin volume mount and created a fresh container instance of jellyfin.</p>
<p>I waited for half an hour for Jellyfin to complete the metadata downloads (movie/show posters, casts, ratings, synopsis, etc), and then I tried to play a movie.. Same error.
<br>
This is insane. I essentially wiped the entire docker instance and recreate a fresh one. And still it does not work.</p>
<h2 id="alternatives">Alternatives</h2>
<p>I decided to cool my mind and watch a show on my phone instead. Since Jellyfin has a mobile app, I just have to enter the server&rsquo;s address and I can watch from my phone.</p>
<p>Then it hit me. All media files are working..
<br>
<br>
I entered the server&rsquo;s address using the IP:Port combo since I did not put the DNS server in my phone&rsquo;s network.
<br>
<br>
I immediately test it out. I go to my browser, instead of using <code>jellyfin.homelab.local</code>, I used <code>192.168.x.x:8096</code>.
<br>
<br>
And it worked!!
<br>
<br>
Now I know this is not fixed yet, but the pool of suspects just became very small.
<br>
<br>
To recap, this is how DNS works in my homelab:
<img loading="lazy" src="/pic9.png" type="" alt="homelab-dns"  title="my-homelab-dns"  /></p>
<p>Clearly, the suspects are between these two: Pihole and Nginx Servers
<br>
Since Nginx is the reverse proxy, I decided to first test my DNS Pihole.
<br>
<br>
The way my DNS is setup is all the domain names are pointed to one IP Address: Nginx. This way, Nginx can be the reverse proxy since pihole DNS cannot handle port numbers.
<br>
<br>
For my testing, I changed the IP address of <code>jellyfin.homelab.local</code> to directly point at the jellyfin server instead of Nginx:
<img loading="lazy" src="/pic10.png" type="" alt="pihole-dns"  title="pihole-dns"  /></p>
<p>Because Pihole cannot handle port numbers, I have to manually enter it in the URL: <code>jellyfin.homelab.local:8096</code>
<br>
<br>
And again, everything works!
<br>
<br>
Pihole is eliminated from the  suspect list. All that remains is the Nginx server.</p>
<h2 id="the-problem">The Problem</h2>
<p>Upon <code>ssh</code>-ing inside the server, I did all of the applicable steps I did in troubleshooting the jellyfin docker: Inspect the <code>docker-compose</code> file, double-check the file ownerships and permissions of the volume mounts, check port disks issues.</p>
<p>And there it was.. As I checked the server&rsquo;s disk utilization:
<img loading="lazy" src="/pic11.png" type="" alt="nginxdisk"  title="nginx-util"  />
The disk was fully utilized, and so nginx cannot properly do its main function because it cannot save new data anymore.
<br>
<br>
In hindsight, this may have been a very short investigation had I went over the basics first instead of the complicated ones. Oh well.. live and learn.
<br>
<br>
I learned a lot with this experience. This is the good thing about having a homelab. I am always learning, re-learning and realizing new things everyday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
