<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bash on Agrielio De Lazo II</title>
    <link>https://avdlii.xyz/tags/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bash on Agrielio De Lazo II</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://avdlii.xyz/img/terminal.png</url>
      <link>https://avdlii.xyz/img/terminal.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 16:24:19 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://avdlii.xyz/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Kubernetes Using Kubeadm</title>
      <link>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/kubeadm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 16:24:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/kubeadm/</guid>
      <description>Creating a working kubernetes cluster from scratch</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I am first learning about <strong>Kubernetes</strong>, I am using <code>minikube</code>. But it was all too easy. I want to learn how to set it up from the ground up. What packages are involved, what dependencies, what configuration files should I look for. The answer to this is <code>kubeadm</code>.</p>
<p><code>kubeadm</code> is a command line command that lets me create a *<em>Kubernetes</em> cluster from scratch. But before I can use<code>kubeadm</code>, I have to install some packages and configure some os-level stuff.</p>
<p>I will use <strong>Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL)</strong> to run my <strong>Kubernetes</strong> cluster. These are the steps in  broad strokes:</p>
<ol>
<li>Install all <code>kubernetes</code> package dependencies</li>
<li>Create and activate modprobe modules for <strong>Kubernetes</strong> networking</li>
<li>Configure kernel parameters using <code>sysctl</code> for networking</li>
<li>Download and setup <code>containerd</code></li>
<li>Download and setup <code>runc</code></li>
<li>Download and configure <code>cni</code></li>
<li>Disable swap on OS</li>
<li>Setup the <strong>Kubernetes</strong> repository on the server</li>
<li>Download <strong>Kubernetes</strong> packages</li>
<li>Create a <code>kubernetes control-plane</code> which will act as the main brain of the <strong>Kubernetes</strong> cluster</li>
<li>Create <code>kubernetes workers</code> and join them to the <code>kubernetes control-plane</code> server</li>
</ol>
<p>I know this is far from perfect but its definitely a start.</p>
<p>With this, I can further learn how <strong>Kubernetes</strong> works on a deeper level. One step at a time..</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
