<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Homelab on Agrielio De Lazo II</title>
    <link>https://avdlii.xyz/tags/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homelab on Agrielio De Lazo II</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://avdlii.xyz/img/terminal.png</url>
      <link>https://avdlii.xyz/img/terminal.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 14:28:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://avdlii.xyz/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Homelab Self-hosting Update</title>
      <link>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/homelab-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 14:28:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/homelab-update/</guid>
      <description>A more robust homelab environment</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This past week, all I did was update and refine my homelab environment. I am doing all the setup on my old Ubuntu PC and deploying my applications on docker containers. It was a lot of funand I am learning a lot.</p>
<p>For those who don&rsquo;t know me, I love watching (and rewatching) movies and TV shows. Especially those that left a mark in my brain. So when I found out that I can self-host my own media server, I was amazed. And with that, I fell into the rabbithole of self-hosting and homelabbing.</p>
<p>I want to share my homelab diagram. This is just the basic setup and I will update it as I go. I might even buy an old mini PC to use as a server. But now, this will do:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/pic6.png" type="" alt="homelab-diagram"  title="Homelab-diagram-1"  /></p>
<h3 id="pi-hole">Pi-hole</h3>
<p>PiHole is a network-wide adblocking application that acts as my DNS for my other applications.</p>
<h3 id="nginx-proxy-manager">Nginx Proxy Manager</h3>
<p>Nginx Proxy Manager is my reverse proxy server for redirecting the server requests on my private network to their respective IP/ports.</p>
<h3 id="jellyfin">Jellyfin</h3>
<p>My self-hosted media server. All the users in our home network can access my Jellyfin server to watch movies and shows.</p>
<h3 id="vaultwarden">Vaultwarden</h3>
<p>My password manager for all my sites. I think this is much safer since this is privately-hosted.</p>
<h3 id="prometheus-grafana-cadvisor">Prometheus, Grafana, CAdvisor</h3>
<p>As I discussed in my previous post, this monitoring stack provides data that is converted into a visualized graphs for monitoring my containers&rsquo; resources.
<br>
<br>
<br>
<br>
As of now, I am deploying all of this in a single docker compose file. But as this setup becomes more static, I am gonna use Portainer for my container management.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelab Ideas</title>
      <link>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/homelab-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:12:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avdlii.xyz/posts/homelab-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Brainstorming homelab ideas</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m considering transforming my Windows PC into a homelab. Currently, it runs both Windows and Ubuntu in dual-boot mode, allowing me to <code>ssh</code> into Ubuntu and create virtual machines using <code>virsh</code> for testing and simulation.</p>
<p>As I research more, I discovered numerous services and applications that I could host on this older PC.</p>
<p>To start, since I primarily use this PC for virtual machines, why not experiment with Proxmox? Additionally, as for watching TV series and movies, hosting my own Jellyfin server sounds exciting. Concerned about managing passwords across different sites? I&rsquo;ll set up my own Bitwarden server.</p>
<p>The possibilities are just too many to ignore so I think I&rsquo;m gonna do it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
